# **AMY CHEN**

Seattle, WA | 206-688-0434 | <u>amychen.dev@gmail.com</u> | <u>www.amychen.dev</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/4myc</u> | Blog: <u>dev.to/4myc</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/4myc</u>

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Versatile front-end engineer with full-stack capability and a background in graphic and web design.

Eager and quick learner keen on utilizing my creative and technical skills to create visually engaging user interfaces and experiences. Passionate about combining code and design to make an impact on users' lives.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

FRONT-END
BACK-END
JavaScript
Rails
React.js
PostgreSQL
Ruby
SQLite
HTML
RESTful APIs
CSS
Git
Material UI
Semantic UI
Bootstrap

## **DESIGN SKILLS**

User Interface Design
Responsive Web Design
Graphic Design
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe InDesign

#### **EDUCATION**

10/2019 - 03/2020

## Flatiron School

Seattle, WA

Full Stack Web Development In-Person Program

06/2006 - 03/2010

#### The Art Institute of Seattle

Seattle, WA

BFA, Graphic Design

08/2005 - 05/2006

#### **University of Central Arkansas**

Conway, AR General Studies

#### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

#### Trip Planner

GitHub Client | GitHub Server

Dynamic single-page app that allows a user to create trips and add a packing list and itinerary to each trip.

- + Collaborated with two team members and built the CRUD app within a 7-day timeline
- + Contributions: Trips page layout and design, new user form, toggle function to view a trip's edit forms, installed and set up Semantic UI, added back-end user validation
- + Utilized Semantic UI interactive elements to style Trips page user interface and improve user experience
- + Front-End: React.js, Semantic UI
- + Back-End: Rails, PostgreSQL

# Leopardy!

<u>GitHub Repo</u>

CLI trivia game about leopards inspired by Jeopardy! and Pup Quiz from The Tonight Show Starring Jimmy Fallon.

- + Full CRUD app built within a 4-day timeline
- + Implemented logic to allow the user to create, update, and delete an account
- + Implemented logic to create three multiple-choice game rounds
- + Incorporated ASCII logo and visual design elements to improve user experience
- + Technologies: Ruby, ActiveRecord

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Bookline Production Assistant Reischling Press Incorporated   Tukwila, WA	11/2018 - 09/2019
Production Specialist & Graphic Designer content26   Seattle, WA	09/2010 - 04/2013
Customer Service Representative Minuteman Press   Seattle, WA	10/2009 - 01/2010
Graphic Design Intern  Washington CEO Magazine   Seattle, WA	08/2008 - 09/2008
Graphic Design Intern  Titan   Seattle, WA	03/2008 - 08/2008